School of Engineering and Applied Science Records, 1884-2017: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 4: Audiovisual Materials, 1902-2007 April; 6 linear feet 7 boxes
  - Videorecordings, 1974-2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 box
    - Leading Change--Wes Harris--DVCAM, 2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
      Conference titled “Leading Change in Science and Technology: A Princeton Engineering Conference for Black Alumni”
    - Leading Change--Kneeland Youngblood, Claire Gmachl, William Massey, Wole Soboyejo--DVCAM, 2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
    - Leading Change--"Increasing Diversity" Panel and Sharad Malik--DVCAM, 2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
    - Leading Change--"Student Leader…the Decades"--DVCAM, 2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
    - Leading Change--Princeton Engineering--Increasing Diversity Panel--Betacam, 2007 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
    - Eric Schmidt--CEO, Novell (E-Quad Room 104), 1998 April; AR.2017.126; 1 tape (Box 192)
  - Lantern Slide Plates, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
    - Appel and Elgin, Performances of Spray and Packed Column Extracting Tolvene-Benzoic Acid-Water, undated; 11 Plates (Box 169)
    - Flooding Velocity of Columns, undated; 6 Plates (Box 169)
    - Chemistry, undated; 1 Box (Box 169)
    - Solvent Extraction - Elgin, undated; 21 Plates (Box 169)
    - Graphical Calculations of Leaching Operations, undated; 6 Plates (Box 169)
    - Miscellaneous Slides of Dean Elgin, undated; 1 Box (Box 169)
  - Greg Olsen's Moon Journey Flag with Seal of Princeton University, circa 2005; AR.2017.126; 1 folder (Box 164)
  - Unmarked Film, undated; 2 Film Canisters (Box 169)
- Series 5: June 2007 Accession, 1992-2000; AR.2009.056; 2 linear feet 2 boxes
  Series 5: June 2007 Accession consists of Dean James Wei files. The files pertain to the Leadership Council, curriculum development and prospect cultivation.
  The order of the materials at the time of transfer to the University Archives has been maintained.
  - Leadership Council Appointments, 1992; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 1)
  - SEAS Leadership Council, 1992; 2 folders (Box 171, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Leadership Council, 1992 May-2000; 9 folders
    - Presents, 1992 May; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - 1993, 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 5)
    - Meeting, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 6)
    - Meeting Presentation, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 7)
    - Meetings, 1993 March 18-1996 March 29; 4 folders
      - 1993 March 18-19, 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 8)
      - 1994 April 21-22, 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 9)
      - 1995 March 30-31, 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 10)
      - 1996 March 28-29, 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 171, Folder 12)
  - Prospect Cultivation, 1992; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 1)
  - Textile Research Institute, 1993; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 2)
  - President’s Campaign Council, 1994-1998; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - Press Release, Gordon Wu Gift, 1995; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - Sollenberger Professorship, 1996; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 5)
  - Development, 1997; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Development, 2nd Round 250th, 1997; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Development, 1997-1998; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 8)
  - Development, 1997; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 9)
  - SEAS Development, 1998; 1 folder (Box 172, Folder 10)
- Series 6: October 2011 Accession, Flying Wind Tunnel Film and Report, 1954-2010; AR.2011.112; 1.21 linear feet 2 boxes (Box 173, Box 174)
  No arrangement action taken or arrangement information not recorded at the time of processing.
  Series 6: October 2011 Accession includes one reel of 16mm film titled Film Report No. 2: Use of an Airship as an Aerodynamic Model Test Carriage, A Joint Investigation by Princeton University and the Air Test and Development Department or the Blimp Film, circa 1960. The film has been transferred to DVD. Also includes a related Department of Aeronautical Engineering Report "A Wind Tunnel Investigation of a Sikorsky S-56 Blade Selection Fitted with the Griswod Leading Edge Blowing Slot," 1954, by D.J. Kike and M. M. Vadas and an article on the Flying Wind Tunnel project, 2010.
- Series 7: April 2011 Accession, 1969-1994; AR.2011.023; 1 linear foot 1 box
  Series 7: April 2011 Accession includes information about the National Society of Black Engineers, the National Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers, the Society of Women Engineers, Tau Beta Pi, and the publication The Princeton Engineer
  The order in which these files came to the Mudd Library has been maintained.
  - Engineering Council Activities, 1969-1994; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
  - National Society of Black Engineers Activities and Correspondence, 1985-1993; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
  - Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers Activities and Correspondence, 1986-1991; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
  - Society of Women Engineers Activities and Correspondence, 1986-1994; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
  - The Princeton Engineer (Publication) Finances and Subscribers, 1988-1991; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
  - Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honor Society Charter and Member Lists, circa 1975; portion of 1 box (Box 175)
- Series 8: June 2012 Accession, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Records, 1975-1997; AR.2012.067; 2 linear feet 2 boxes
  Series 8: June 2012 Accession, Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Records includes information on the Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Advisory Board, Geophysical Fluid Dynamics, the Von Neuman Building, Faculty Meetings and also includes staff publication lists.
  Files that contain faculty personnel records are restricted for 75 years from date of creation; these restrictions are noted in the folder list below. The remainder of the records are restricted for a period of 25 years from the date of their creation.
  - Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Advisory Board Meetings, 1977-1996; 1 box (Box 177)
  - Geophysical Fluid Dynamics, 1975-1987; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - SEAS Dean Hisashi Kobayashi, 1986-1989; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
    Restricted for 75 years from the date of creation
  - Von Neumann Building (Formerly IDA), Memoranda, 1975-1983; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - Von Neumann Building (Formerly IDA), Memoranda and Plans, circa 1975-1976; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Full Faculty Meeting, 1995-1996; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Full Faculty Meeting, 1996-1997; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1995-1996; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1996-1997; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1997; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1997 April 02; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1997 May 14; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Full Faculty Meeting, 1997 May 13; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Tenured Faculty Meeting, 1997 April 2; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Publication Lists, 1981-1987; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
  - MAE Publication Lists, 1975-1981; portion of 1 box (Box 178)
- Series 9: Chemical Engineering Achievement Award for Contribution to the Atomic Bomb Project, 1946; 1.2 linear feet (Cabinet 5, Drawer 15)
  Series 9 consists of a certificate given to the university in recognition of its contribution to the Atomic Bomb Project in the field of Chemical Engineering. The certificate award was given by "Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering" on February 26, 1946.
  Series 9 is open for research.
- Series 10: Guggenheim Laboratory Time Capsule Materials, circa 1964; AR.2012.089; 0.21 linear feet 1 box (Box 179)
  The Guggenheim Basic Research Laboratory time capsule materials include photographs of the lab building and personnel; press release from the cornerstone laying ceremony; list of Princeton University Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Sciences Guggenheim Laboratory theses and dissertations; 1964 laboratories annual report; and related materials.
  Series 10 is open for research.
- Series 11: Public Websites, 2015-2017; 7 websites
  This series contains captures of the websites of the School as well as its six subsidiary departments. Found within each website will be information about courses, students, requirements, and faculty.
  Full text searching of this series' archived websites is available through the Archive-It interface.
  The original arrangement of the files was maintained.
  Series 11: Public Websites is open for research.
  - School of Engineering and Applied Science Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
    The Princeton University School of Engineering and Applied Science Website contains information for prospective and current undergraduate and graduate students including a description of the departments within the school and its interdisciplinary certificate programs and centers, a directory of faculty members and their research areas, alumni news, and related topics.
  - Department of Computer Science Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
  - Department of Chemical and Biological Engineering Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
  - Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
  - Department of Electrical Engineering Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
  - Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Public Website, 2016-2017; 1 website
  - Department of Operations Research and Financial Engineering Public Website, 2015-2017; 1 website
- Series 12: Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1997 February 19-2012 October 2; AR.2016.039; 2 linear feet 2 boxes
  Series 12: Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Faculty Meeting Minutes contains agendas, supplementary information, and minutes from full and tenured faculty meetings from 1997 through 2012. The series includes sensitive personnel information..
  The series is restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1997 September 24; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1997 November 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1997 February 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 September 21; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 October 12; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 February 11; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 April 1; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 September 15; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full and tenured faculty meeting minutes, 1998 October; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full faculty meeting minutes, 1998 November 17; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 November 10; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 December 2; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 October 13-1998 November 10; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenure and promotion votes, 1999 November; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 April 6; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 May 18; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 March 24; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 March 3; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 February 2; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 December 7; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 September 28; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 November-1999 December; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 September 28; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 October 26; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 January 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 September 21; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 November-1999 December; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1999 February 17; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 1998 September 15; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Dean of the Faculty Annual Meeting, 1999 October; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Advisory Council meeting agenda, 2000 September 28; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 September 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda, 2000 December 5; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda, 2000 October 17; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 November 7; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Special faculty meeting agenda, 2000 October 3; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 February 1; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full and Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 April 18; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 February 15; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2000 February 22; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2001 November 26; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda, 2001 September 25; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2001 October 23; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda, 2001 October 2; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2001 November 13; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting minutes, 2001 February 6; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda and minutes, 2001 February 20; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 December 10; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 November 22; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 November 4; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 January 8; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda and minutes, 2002 January 21; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - General faculty meeting agenda and minutes, 2002 February 5; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 February 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 March 12; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 March 26; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 April 8; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 April 22; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 May 7; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 May 21; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 September 23; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2002 October 4; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - meeting minutes, 2003 August 12; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 October 15; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 November 11; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 November 18; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 December 23; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 February 4; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - meeting minutes, 2003 March 13; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 May 27; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - meeting minutes, 2003 May 19; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 February 20; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 March 6; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 April 8; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 April 24; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 May 6; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 September 15; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured Faculty meeting minutes, 2003 December 9; portion of 1 box (Box 180)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2005 January 18; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2005 January 18; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 November 15; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 October 11; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2005 February 8; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2005 March 29; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 April 5; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 April 19; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 May 3; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 May 17; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2005 February 1; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2005 September 20; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 April 4; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 February 7; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 February 21; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2006 February 14; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 January 17; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 May 2; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 May 16; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 January 17; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - 2004-2005 Annual Report, meeting agendas and correspondence, 2001-2006; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 November 21; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 September 19; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 October 3; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2006 November 7; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 December 19; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2006 October 17; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 May 15; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 May 1; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full professors faculty meeting minutes, 2007 October 23; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 October 1; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 November 13; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full and tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2007 December 11; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 February 6; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 February 20; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 March 6; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 September 18; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 February 19; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2008 February 5; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 April 8; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 March 4; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 March 24; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 April 22; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 September 9; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 September 22; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2008 November 11; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2008 December 9; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2007 April 3; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 February 10; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting materials, 2009 March 31; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 February 17; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 April 14; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 May 14; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 October 13; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 December 8; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2009 October 27; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Faculty meeting minutes, 2010 October 19; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2010 September 21; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2010 May 3; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2010 April 13; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2010 February 13; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2010 November 9; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2010 March 2; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - General faculty meeting minutes, 2011 February 15; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2011 February 8; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2011 September 27; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - General faculty meeting minutes, 2011 November 15; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - General faculty meeting minutes, 2011 September 13; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - General and tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2011 April 26; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2012 February 14; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Full Faculty meeting minutes, 2012 February 21; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2012 February 7; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - General faculty meeting minutes, 2012 October 2; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting agenda, 2012 May 29; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
  - Tenured faculty meeting minutes, 2012 April 3; portion of 1 box (Box 181)
- Series 13: Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Faculty Meeting Minutes, 2013-2017; AR.2017.117; Digital Files: 39
  Series 13: Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering Faculty Meeting Minutes contains agendas, supplementary information, and minutes from full and tenured faculty meetings from the academic years of 2014-2017.